Guide to the Motion picture press kit collection, 1968-2004
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 1: Films, 1988-2004
  - L. 627, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Promotional color booklet and one photograph.
  - La Buche, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Laada, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Printed (in French) material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis
  - Laissez-Passer, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film stills, and film synopsis.
  - Land and Freedom, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - The Land Girls, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Sundance Film Festival production notes. Three color slides and three promotional photographs.
  - Last Night, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Last Orders, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - The Last Seduction, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Last September, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Color promotional booklet including film stills printed in French and English.
  - Lawn Dogs, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - L.I.E, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Life is Sweet, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Three promotional photographs.
  - The Life of David Gale, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Promotional booklet containing: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with promotional film stills.
  - The Limey, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Little Voice, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Live Flesh, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lone Star, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Six color slides and seven promotional black and white photographs.
  - The Long Day Closes, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Two sheets of handwritten notes.
  - Looking for Richard, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1996 Cannes Film festival.
  - Lost in Translation, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, soundtrack information, and film synopsis.
  - The Loss of Sexual Innocence, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Love, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Love After Love, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis in both French and English. Sixteen promotional photographs.
  - Love and Death on Long Island, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Promotional booklet for the 1997 Cannes Film festival printed in both French and English.
  - Love and Other Catastrophes, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Love is the Devil: Study for a Portrait of Francis Bacon, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Six promotional postcards.
  - Love's Labours Lost, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Love Serenade, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Promotional packet created for the 1996 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Loved, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lovers of the Arctic Circle, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Il Lungo Silenzio, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Promotional booklet and printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. All material printed in both English and French.
  - The Luzhin Defence, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ma Vie en Rose, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1997 Cannes Film Festival. Printed in both French and English..
  - Magnificat, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Promotional color booklet printed in both French and English.
  - Man of the Century, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Man on the Train, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Color promotional booklet printed for the 2002 Venice Film Festival.
  - The Man Without a Past, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mansfield Park, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Marie Baie Des Anges, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Marius et Jeannette, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Marquise, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Max et Jeremie, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Film synopsis printed in both English and French.
  - Me You Them, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Memento, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - A Merry War, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Metroland, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Mi Vida Loca, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Four promotional photographs.
  - Mifune, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Minor Mishaps, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Color promotional booklet including film information and stills.
  - Mister Johnson, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Five promotional photographs.
  - Moi Ivan, Toi Abraham, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Two promotional photographs.
  - Monsoon Wedding, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Mr. Death: The Rise and Call of Fred A. Leauchter, Jr., 1999 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Promotional color booklet, two sheets of handwritten notes, an article from the New York Observer and one from the New Yorker.
  - Mrs. Brown, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Mrs. Dalloway, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Mrs. Parker and the Vicious Circle, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Three color slides.
  - Mumford, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Muriel's Wedding, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Promotional booklet printed for the 1994 Cannes Film Festival.
  - The Muse, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Music of the Heart, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - My Generation, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - My Son the Fanatic, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Color promotional booklet with detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - The Myth of Fingerprints, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Naked, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Promotional booklet with detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Four promotional photographs.
  - Nelly and Monsieur Arnaud, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Nil by Mouth, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - The Ninth Gate, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Eight promotional photographs and eight color slides.
  - No, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - No Man's Land, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Eleven color slides and one page of handwritten notes.
  - Noi albinoi, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Not One Less, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Related Archival Materials note
  - Nurse Betty, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - O Brother, Where Art Thou?, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Promotional color booklet including detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Six promotional photographs.
  - One Day in September, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Onegin, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - The Opposite of Sex, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - The Opportunists, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Paradise Lost, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, historical content relevant to the film, and film synopsis. Articles from the New York Times and The Star Ledger.
  - Paulina, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Promotional package including production notes, post cards, photographs and several articles and movie reviews.
  - Permanent Midnight, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Persuasion, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Peter Pan, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    Promotional booklet with detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with film stills.
  - The Piano, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Color promotional booklet printed for the 1993 Cannes Film Festival.
  - The Pianist, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 2002 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Pieces of April, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Place Vendome, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pleasantville, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Pollock, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Possession, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Eight sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Priest, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Princess Mononoke, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Prisoner of the Mountains, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also includes several articles about, and reviews of the film.
  - Prospero's Books, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - A Pure Formality, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Raining Stones, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Seven promotional photographs, four color slides, and one full size poster.
  - Ridicule, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - The Ring, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with film stills.
  - A River Runs Through It, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Road Home, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. One sheet of promotional photographs and four color slides.
  - Road To Perdition, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Promotional color booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with film stills and a copy of the screen play adapted into a graphic novel.
  - Romance, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - A Room for Romeo Brass, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Two sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Les Roseaux Sauvages, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Rosencrantz & Guildenstern Are Dead, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Six sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Rosetta, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Promotional booklet for the Cannes Film Festival 1999 printed in both French and English.
  - Rosie, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Ruby in Paradise, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Oversized color promotional booklet and one newspaper article.
  - Safe, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Safety of Objects, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Saving Grace, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Promotional color booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - The School of Rock, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, soundtrack information and film synopsis.
  - The Season of Men, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Promotional color booklet with detail production information.
  - Secretary, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Letter from Lions Gate Films announcing the pre-screening schedule for the film.
  - Secrets and Lies, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Promotional color booklet printed in both English and French.
  - A Self Made Hero, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Promotional booklet including film synopsis, interviews with cast and crew and selected filmographies.
  - Sense and Sensibility, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Sexy Beast, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Shall We Dance, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Shanghai Triad, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - The Shape of Things, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Three sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Shattered Glass, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - The Shawshank Redemption, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Shine, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Photocopy of a promotional booklet.
  - A Short Film About Killing, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Several copies of articles about, and reviews of the film.
  - A Short Film About Love, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Shower, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Les Silences du Palais, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Photocopy of promotional material.
  - Simpatico, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Slam, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Slaves to the Underground, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - SLC Punk, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Sling Blade, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Smoke Signals, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Smoking, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Snakes and Ladders, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Sofie, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Promotional color flyer.
  - Solas, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Some Nudity Required, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Son's Room, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Southern Comfort, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Spanish Prisoner, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Spellbound, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Spirit, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Color promotional booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film stills, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with film stills.
  - State and Main, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Statement, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies,interviews, and film synopsis.
  - The Station Agent, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Stealing Beauty, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Color promotional booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film stills, and film synopsis.
  - Stevie, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Storytelling, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - The Straight Story, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Promotional book printed in color and including a film synopsis, film stills, notes about the production and cast and crew.
  - Sunday, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - A Summer's Tale, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Suzaku, 1997; Promotional material printed for the 1997 Cannes Film Festival. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Sweet and Lowdown, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Edes Emma, draga Bobe - vazlatok, aktok (Sweet Emma, Dear Bobe), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    Promotional flyer printed in English, French and German.
  - The Sweet Hereafter, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Swoon, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Sylvia, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Taboo, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1999 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Tango Feroz, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - The Tango Lesson, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Thank You and Goodnight, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - That's the Way I Like It, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Article from The Hollywood Reporter.
  - Things to Do in Denver When You're Dead, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Three color slides, and four sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Thirteen Conversations About One Thing, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - This World, Then the Fireworks, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Six promotional photographs and five color slides.
  - Three Colors: Blue (Trois couleurs: bleu), 1993 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Three Colors: Red (Trois couleurs: rouge), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    Color promotional booklet printed in both English and French. Newspaper review of the film.
  - Three Seasons, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Titanic Town, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Time Regained, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Color promotional booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis.
  - Tito and Me, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Promotional flyer printed in both French and English.
  - Total Eclipse, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Touch of Evil (Re-Edited version), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Printed material including: explanation of the re-edit process, detailed cast and crew list, and film synopsis.
  - Trainspotting, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1996 Cannes Film Festival. Two sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Trees Lounge, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Troublesome Creek: A Midwestern, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - The Truth About Charlie, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Tu Ridi, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Printed material including: film stills, detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Tully, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - The Tulse Luper Suitcases, Part 1: The Moab Story, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Promotional booklet in the style of a journal, printed for the 2003 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Twelfth Night, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Two copies of a promotional booklet that includes: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Twenty Four Seven, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Four sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Twin Falls Idaho, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Ulee's Gold, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Under Heaven, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - The Usual Suspects, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Three color slides and two promotional photographs.
  - Van Gogh, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    Promotional booklets printed in French, one containing excerpts from the script the other with cast photos. Biography and filmography of director Maurice Pialat also printed in French.
  - Vanya on 42nd Street, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Voices From a Locked Room, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Waking Life, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Waking the Dead, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - The War Room, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - The War Zone, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    Promotional booklet including film stills, synopsis and the Sundance Film Festival screening schedule.
  - Water Drops on Burning Rocks, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    Printed material including: interviews, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also includes a promotional color flyer.
  - The Way of the Gun, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Welcome to the Dollhouse, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Wendemi, l'enfant du bon Dieu, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Promotional flyer for the 1993 Cannes Film Festival. Printed in both French and English.
  - The Whole Wide World, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Wild Man Blues, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Wild Things, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Seven sheets of promotional photographs.
  - Wilde, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Windhorse, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - The Wings of the Dove, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - The Winter Guest, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Five color slides and two sheets of promotional photographs.
  - With a Friend Like Harry, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Wonderland, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Y Tu Mama Tambien, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The Yards, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - You Can Count on Me, 2000
  - The Young Poisoner's Handbook, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Young Soul Rebels, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Zhou Yu's Train, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Preliminary press notes.
- Series 2: Miscellaneous, 1988-2004
  Scope and Content
  This series includes printed material related to the film industry. Included is a guide to movie distribution, a booklet announcing the release of several silent films, and a list of upcoming new releases.
  - A Guide to Self Distribution, 1988-2004 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - A Milestone Film and Video Release, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Newsletter and articles about the release of several silent and early sound films, previously unavailable on video.
  - Motion Picture Press Releases (Box 15, Folder 19)
    A list of selected films and information about their press kits.
- Series 3: Oversize, 1968-2000
  This series contains large format press kits and promotional material. The material in this series includes collectible and one of a kind promotional packages.
  - 2001: A Space Odyssey, 1968 (Box 16)
    Original souvenir book released in conjunction with the film. Features large scale film stills and information on the production of the film and its cast and crew.
  - Barb Wire, 1996 (Box 16)
    Large scale press kit printed on cardboard with production notes, color slides, and issue one of the comic book Barb Wire.
  - Girlfight, 2000 (Box 16)
    Oversized promotional booklet printed for the 2000 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Titus, 1999 (Box 16)
    Several copies of production notes and oversized promotional booklet featuring large film stills.